What you're doing,
ما تفعله،
right now, at this very moment,
الآن، في هذه اللحظة بالذات،
is killing you.
يقتلك.
More than cars or the Internet
أكثر من السيارات أو الإنترنت
or even that little mobile device we keep talking about,
أو حتى الجهاز المحمول الصغيرالذي مازلنا نتحدث عنه،
the technology you're using the most almost every day
أكثر من تكنولوجيا تستخدمها كل يوم تقريباً
is this, your tush.
هي هذه، موخرتك.
Nowadays people are sitting 9.3 hours a day,
في هذه الأيام الناس يجلسون 9.3 ساعات يوميا،
which is more than we're sleeping, at 7.7 hours.
وهي أكثر من الوقت نومنا, 7.7 ساعات.
Sitting is so incredibly prevalent,
الجلوس شائع جداً بشكل لا يصدق،
we don't even question how much we're doing it,
ونحن لا نسأل حتى كم نحن نفعل ذلك،
and because everyone else is doing it,
ونظراً لأن الجميع يفعل ذلك،
it doesn't even occur to us that it's not okay.
فإنه لا يتبين لنا أنه ليس جيداً.
In that way, sitting has become
وبهذه الطريقة، فقد أصبح الجلوس
the smoking of our generation.
كالتدخين لجيلنا.
Of course there's health consequences to this,
بالطبع هناك عواقب صحية لهذا،
scary ones, besides the waist.
مخيفه، بجانب إلى الخصر.
Things like breast cancer and colon cancer
أشياء مثل سرطان الثدي وسرطان القولون
are directly tied to our lack of physical [activity],
وترتبط مباشرة إلى افتقارنا إلى البدنية [نشاط]،
Ten percent in fact, on both of those.
عشرة في المئة في الواقع،
Six percent for heart disease,
ستة في المئة للإصابة بأمراض القلب
seven percent for type 2 diabetes,
سبعة في المئة لمرض السكري من النوع 2،
which is what my father died of.
وهو النوع الذي توفي والدي منه.
Now, any of those stats should convince each of us
الآن، أي من تلك الإحصائيات يجب أن تقنع كل واحد منا
to get off our duff more,
لتجنب الجلوس أكثر،
but if you're anything like me, it won't.
ولكن إذا كنت مثلي، فهذا لا ينفع
What did get me moving was a social interaction.
ما جعلني أتحرك هو التفاعل الاجتماعي.
Someone invited me to a meeting,
شخص ما دعاني إلى اجتماع،
but couldn't manage to fit me in
ولكن لم يستطع أن يضعني
to a regular sort of conference room meeting, and said,
مؤتمرعادية في قاعة الاجتماع، وقال:
"I have to walk my dogs tomorrow. Could you come then?"
"يجب علي إصطحاب كلاب في نزهة غداً. هل يمكن أن تأتي بعد ذلك؟ "
It seemed kind of odd to do,
يبدو غريباً نوع ما القيام بذلك،
and actually, that first meeting, I remember thinking,
وفي الواقع، تلك الجلسة الأولى، أتذكر أنني كنت اأفكر،
"I have to be the one to ask the next question,"
"يجب أكون الشخص الذي يطرح السؤال التالي،"
because I knew I was going to huff and puff
لأنني كنت أعرف أنني سوف أتضمر
during this conversation.
خلال هذه المحادثة.
And yet, I've taken that idea and made it my own.
ولكن، لقد أخذت هذه الفكرة وجعلتها ملكي .
So instead of going to coffee meetings
لذا بدلاً من الذهاب إلى إجتماعات القهوه
or fluorescent-lit conference room meetings,
أو إجتماعات غرف أجتماع ذو الإضاء الفلورية
I ask people to go on a walking meeting,
أطلب من الناس الذهاب إلى الإجتماع سيراً على الأقدام،
to the tune of 20 to 30 miles a week.
على تناغم 20 إلى 30 ميلاً في الأسبوع.
It's changed my life.
لقد غيرت حياتي.
But before that, what actually happened was,
ولكن قبل ذلك، كان ما حدث فعلا،
I used to think about it as,
أعدت على أن أفكر في الأمر انه،
you could take care of your health,
يمكنك أن تعتني بصحتك،
or you could take care of obligations,
أو يمكنك أن تعتني بالاتزامات المترتبه،
and one always came at the cost of the other.
و دائماً واحد ياتي على حساب الآخر.
So now, several hundred of these walking meetings later,
حتى الآن، بعد مئات من هذا المشي الى الاجتماعات،
I've learned a few things.
لقد تعلمت بعض الاشياء.
First, there's this amazing thing
أولاً، هناك هذا الشيء المدهش
about actually getting out of the box
حول الخروج عن المالؤف
that leads to out-of-the-box thinking.
والذي يؤدي إلى التفكير خارج المالؤف.
Whether it's nature or the exercise itself, it certainly works.
سواء كانت طبيعة أو الممارسة نفسها، فإنها تعمل بالتأكيد.
And second, and probably the more reflective one,
والثانية، وربما امر أكثر إنعكاسا،
is just about how much each of us
هو عن كم من بيننا
can hold problems in opposition
يمكنه أن يقاوم المشاكل
when they're really not that way.
عندما تكون ليست حقا بهذه الطريقة.
And if we're going to solve problems
وإذا اذا اردنا حل المشاكل
and look at the world really differently,
وننظر إلى العالم حقاً بطريقة مختلفة،
whether it's in governance or business
سواء إذا كان في الحكومه أو الأعمال الحرة
or environmental issues, job creation,
أو المواضيع البيئية، وخلق فرص العمل،
maybe we can think about how to reframe those problems
ونحن ربما يمكن التفكير في كيفية إعادة طرح تلك المشاكل
as having both things be true.
وكما كل الأشياء وقد يكون صحيحاً.
Because it was when that happened
لأنه عندما حدث ذلك
with this walk-and-talk idea
مع فكرة السيرعلى الأقدام والحديث
that things became doable and sustainable and viable.
أن الأمور أصبحت قابلة للتنفيذ ومستدامة وقابلة للحياة.
So I started this talk talking about the tush,
وهكذا بدأت هذا الحديث عن المؤخره،
so I'll end with the bottom line, which is,
لذا سوف انتهي بخلاصه الموضوع، والتي هي،
walk and talk.
المشي والحديث.
Walk the talk.
مشي الحديث.
You'll be surprised at how fresh air drives fresh thinking,
سوف تستغرب كيف أن الهواء النظيف يقود الى تفكير متجدد،
and in the way that you do,
وفي الطريقة التي تقوم بها،
you'll bring into your life an entirely new set of ideas.
سوف تجلب لك في حياتك مجموعة جديدة تماما من الأفكار.
Thank you.
شكرا.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)